<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">Mary Matha College</string>
    <string name="bold" tools:ignore="ReferenceType">@font/latobold</string>
    <string name="regular" tools:ignore="ReferenceType">@font/latoregular</string>
    <string name="light" tools:ignore="ReferenceType">@font/latolight</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="start">Start</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>

    <string name="about_college">Started in the Year 1995,  affiliated to the Kannur University,
        Mary Matha Arts and Science College is a Government-Aided College, managed by the Roman
        Catholic Diocese of Mananthavady. There are Seven Under Graduate Programs (B.A. Functional
        English, B.Sc. Mathematics, Zoology, Computer Science, Physics, Chemistry, and B. Com with
        Computer Applications),Two Post Graduate Programme in Mathematics and Computer Science, Five
        Research Programs leading to M. Phil. and Ph.D. in Mathematics (Kannur University), Malayalam
        (Kannur University), Zoology (Kannur University), Computer Science (Kannur University) and Physical
        Education (Kannur University) and Two Research Centres in Mathematics and Zoology.</string>
    <string name="ncc">A unit of the National Cadet Corps consisting of 62 cadets (1-platoon)
        comprising men and women is functioning in the college. This is an Army Wing under 1
        (Ker) Arty Bty. N. C. C. Thalassery and Lt Dr Rajeev Thomas is the NCC Officer.
        The Kannur University awards 3% Grace Marks for the ‘B’ Certificate holders and 4%
        for the ‘C’ Certificate holders. Likewise the Cadets who attend the Summer Camp and
        the Republic Day Pared Camp are eligible for 6% and 7% Grace Marks respectively.
        In addition to that the Cadets completing two years in NCC will get weightage marks
        for admission to various courses. Students who pass the B and C Examinations will find
        it easy to get commissioned posts in the Defense Service.</string>
    <string name="nss">
The College has two units of the National Service Scheme (Unit No. 33 and 46 of the Kannur University).
        The N. S. S. Units facilitate training for 200 students in Social Work. The Units are under the
        supervision of Mr Toby K Joseph and Mr Binoy Joseph, the Program Officers. The units have undertaken
        a number of programs that help the students to have a socially committed attitude in their education.
        The volunteers are trained to preserve human values in their life along with the honours and titles that
        they achieve in their academic tenure. To accomplish this NSS organizes the following activities. Orientation
        Programme, Special Camping Programme, Environment enrichment programs, Health awareness programs, Educational Programs,
        Observe important days, Women Empowerment Programs, Social Service Programs, Production Oriented Programs, Relief and Rehabilitation
        work during Natural calamities etc</string>
    <string name="ssp">The Scholar Support Programme, part of the ‘New Initiatives in Higher Education’
        initiated by the Department of Higher Education, Govt. of Kerala aims at imparting additional support
        to students in curricular areas of weakness. The pilot phase of the programme that has been introduced
        in the  academic year 2014-2015 would target the First semester Degree programme (B.A./B.Sc/B.Com) being
        offered by the four Universities of the State viz., Kerala, MG, Calicut and Kannur Universities. Subjects
        in which additional curricular support would be offered have been selected based on a results analysis
        work carried out based on results from the affiliated Colleges of Kerala. Mr Regi Francis, Asst. Professor
        in Commerce coordinates the program</string>
    <string name="wws"> Walk With a Scholar (WWS) Programme is another new Initiative Programme of Higher Education Department.
        It has been observed that the students in Arts, Science and Commerce Colleges do not get necessary orientation,
        to prepare them for employment or guidance necessary to select areas for higher study. Walk With a Scholar (WWS) scheme
        proposes to arrange specialized mentoring programmes for students in the Under Graduate Programmes in Arts, Science and
        Commerce and to provide guidance for their future.The scheme introduces the idea of mentoring and builds on the concept of a
        mentor as a “Guide and Friend”. The Scheme aims at giving necessary orientation to bright students who can excel in their disciplines,
        to give them necessary guidance,, motivation; goal orientation and mental support to identify appropriate areas for higher study as well as
        future employment. For the purpose of mentoring, two categories of mentors are identified. The first is Internal Mentor and the second is External
        Mentor. The Internal Mentor is a faculty from the institution in which the scholar is studying. External Mentors are identified from persons who
        excel in their disciplines and professions as found necessary according to the local needs of the institution/ students.The programme is open for
        30 students of the first year of the Under Graduate Programme of study in a college.</string>

    <string name="asap"> To address the concern of the growing educated-unemployment rates of the State, the SSDP or
        State Skill Development Project was enacted, in the year 2012. This was following the realization that Kerala
        has the human resource and the potential to soar up to become a radial point for skilled manpower to the world by
        virtue of its demographic dividend. SSDP involves the participation of industries and training partners to execute
        the project tactically branched into two, ASAP (Additional Skill Acquisition Programme) and ASEP (Additional Skills
        Enhancement Programme). ASAP, under the General and Higher Education Departments, works on the preventive side by training
        Higher Secondary and Graduate students, offering skill courses to students in need of immediate employment. ASEP, under
        the Department of Labour, on the curative side offers enhancement training to educated unemployed youth. Funded by ADB,
        ASAP has now spread out into 1052 educational institutions across the state, offering 83 courses from 24 sectors, and is
        expanding skill training services to all age groups through the innovative idea of Community Skill Parks. Ms Jisha T E,
        Asst Professor in Computer Science coordinates the program.</string>
    <string name="ignu">IGNOU was founded to serve the Indian population by means of distance and open education, providing quality
        higher education opportunities to all segments of society. It also aims to encourage, coordinate and set standards for distance
        and open education in India, and to strengthen the human resources of India through education.[4][5] Apart from teaching and research,
        extension and training form the mainstay of its academic activities. It also acts as a national resource centre, and serves to promote and
        maintain standards of distance education in India.[5] IGNOU hosts the Secretariats of the SAARC Consortium on Open and Distance Learning
        (SACODiL) and the Global Mega Universities Network (GMUNET), initially supported by UNESCO</string>

</resources>